

IT PROFESSIONAL

CONTACT



PROFILE

With degrees in Applied Computing and Networking, I have over 15 years experience providing technical support and systems management. I have worked in business and academic sectors to deliver end-user support, hardware/software installation and configuration, process improvement, IT budget savings and training. I am always interested in learning new skills and technologies and applying that knowledge to solve problems and improve user experiences. My extracurricular interests include music production, tech, film and travel.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- · Microsoft Windows and Server
- · Active Directory
- Group Policy
- Office 365
- Networking
- Helpdesk
- Virtual Machines
- Databases
- Security
- CRM
- · Cloud Computing
- Visual Studio
- Scripting
- Web Design
- Linux
- MacOS
- RFID
- · Audio/Visual Systems
- All types of PC hardware

LANGUAGES

English - Native

Spanish - Working Proficiency

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Administrator

Igoli Fundición S.L., Madrid

July 2017 - June 2022

- Responsible for maintaining all IT systems and equipment at a precious metals business in Alcobendas
- Managing Windows Servers with Active Directory and Group Policy for office clients
- Transforming existing data management processes from Excel to SQL database, streamlining data input while preventing errors
- Creating internal web application for improved customer management and websites for the commercial business, including taking stock photos and writing a WordPress plugin to calculate prices
- Designing and implementing RFID tracking system for jewellery items and CCTV remote access for security
- Creating virtual machines for Windows Server redundancy and PowerShell scripts for management
- Maintaining onsite and offsite backups, performing hardware diagnosis and repairs, network security and printer management
- Writing technical documentation and training staff in usage of IT systems and processes

Head of IT

IGR Green S.L., Madrid

Jan 2021 - Mar 2022

- Creating IT infrastructure and promotional resources for a renewable energy/solar panel startup
- Designing and building websites and PowerPoint/PDF materials for commercial presentations
- Creating a Blazor-based web application with SQL backend for data input and management
- · Setting up office LAN and networked devices
- · Configuring cloud-based solutions for web application hosting

EDUCATION

BSc Applied Computing

Teesside University 2013-2014

FdSc Applied Networking

Teesside University 2011-2013

A Levels

St. Brendan's College 2002

GCSEs

St. Mary Redcliffe School 1999

KEY SKILLS

- Wide breadth of technical knowledge and practical IT experience
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills
- Efficient time management and prioritising of tasks in demanding work environments
- Capable of translating technical concepts for nontechnical people
- Versatile and flexible
- Ability to relate to a wide range of people
- Sense of humour as well as remaining calm and approachable in a crisis

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance English Teacher

Various, Madrid

Sept 2016 - Feb 2018

· Working in a variety of academies teaching English to professionals

Language Assistant

IES Ciudad de Jaén, Madrid

Sept 2014 - July 2016

 Working in a bilingual high school in the Orcasitas area of Madrid, providing students and teachers with a native English speaker to facilitate foreign language development in 11-18 year olds

Bartender

Brudenell Social Club, Leeds

Oct 2012 - July 2014

 Providing bar service in a busy bar and live venue, handling customer queries and complaints, ticket sales, moving stage gear and fixing equipment faults (Part time job whilst undertaking BSc in Applied Computing)

IT Technician

St Mary Redcliffe & Temple School, Bristol

Sept 2005 - Nov 2010

- Working as part of a team of 4 to provide campus-wide technical support to a large school, interacting regularly with 200 teachers and 1500 students
- Broadening my skills to diagnose and repair many types of PC, Macintosh, networking, printing, audio/visual hardware and ICT software
- Active Directory/Group Policy, Microsoft Exchange and VMware ESX Server installation and management
- Supporting 600+ desktop clients and 200+ laptops via phone, email and remote admin and classroom/office visits
- Responsible for completing projects to specification and tight deadlines, including being tasked with a £100,000 purchasing budget for new desktops, obtaining competitive quotes in response to my specifications

IT Administrator

Trinity College, Bristol

2004 - 2006

- Supporting desktops, networks and printers in an adult theological college, responsible for managing routing issues, firewall, internet proxy, backup systems and client software installs
- Enabling students and teachers to work and learn by adapting to manage a Linux-based network on a minimal budget